Kobato, it's all in pieces.
Oh? I'm sorry!
Do we get to have cake from Bakery Tirol
for Christmas again this year?
Oh, yes.
Santa will come, won't he?
I'm sure he will.
What are you doing, Yuzuru?
I'm making it so that it will fit lots of presents.
Let me help you!
Oww...
I-I'm sorry!
Never mind.
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
That outfit... it's a Santa suit, isn't it?
Yes. Fujimoto dresses up as
Santa for us every year.
Who else is there?
You're right. Thank you.
...White Christmas.
I wonder if Fujimoto is still angry with me.
Dobato.
Yes?
We don't have time to be worried
about that right now, do we?
Yes?
The kompeito! Do you remember?!
Y-Yes sir!
Kobato?
Domoto.
I've been waiting. It's been a long
day for you, hasn't it?
Oh, I'm fine!
I'll walk you home.
If you don't mind, that is.
Oh of course not.
Thank you very much.
Christmas is so sparkly and pretty.
It is. Kobato, is there something
that you're wishing for?
Huh? Wishing for?
Well, thanks to the bazaar, there was enough
money to buy new toys. Hmm...
Then can I choose something
that I think will suit you?
A present.
For me?
Sure. It's Christmas.
I wonder what you'd like.
Hey, you're sure working hard.
Even during Christmas?
I don't mind. Christmas doesn't
mean anything to me anyway.
Is something wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
Kobato?
Nothing!
Guess we'd better get going. See you around.
Kobato, I see you still haven't
reconciled with Fujimoto.
I don't know. I don't think he likes me anymore.
He's not like he usually is.
He doesn't say nasty things anymore.
He won't even look at me.
Is that right?
It's been on my mind... for a long time.
You've done nothing wrong, Kobato.
And I'm sure Fujimoto would agree.
He just doesn't know how to admit it.
So don't worry about it.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
My pleasure.
Can I see you again tomorrow?
Huh? Ah, sure.
Then I'll wait for you in front of the kindergarten.
Oh, no. It would be too cold.
I'll be waiting.
Oh... but...
I'll be all right.
So, see you tomorrow.
Okay.
It's Christmas inside, too.
Oh, Ioryogi-san, I'd better get you a present, too.
What would you like to have?
Kompeito! A whole bottle full of them!
I-I know that!
Oh, I know.
This. I made it for you, Ioryogi-san! Here!
Yay! Ioryogi-san has turned into a reindeer!
Dobato!
Whew. Give me a break.
Oh no! I'm late!
Good morning.
Oh, good morning!
You're earlier than usual today, Kobato.
Yes. I need to prepare for the Christmas party.
I see.
Kobato, if you're free this
evening, please come over.
We're having our own Christmas party.
Mother is going to cook a big meal for us.
Please join us if you can.
Yes. Thank you very much.
Good morning.
Oh, you too, Fujimoto. Please come.
Come to our Christmas party.
I have to work tonight. Besides, Christmas...
Then, good luck with your job. Have a good day.
Move along now. You need to get going, too.
Okay!
See you later!
Kobato?
Everyone is so excited about Christmas,
but Fujimoto seems sad.
It's all my fault. The other day,
I shouldn't have...
That's not it.
It was Christmas Eve one year
when Fujimoto became alone.
Merry Christmas!
To Mother
Mother!
Are you all right, dear?
I'm... fine.
You are? That's good.
Fujimoto's mother never
came home since that day.
Shortly after that, Fujimoto was
taken in by Sayaka's father.
Sorry I'm late.
No worries. Now. Shall we begin the party?
I'm ready.
Then Fujimoto.
Wait until everyone calls you and then come in.
Okay.
Kobato.
Yes.
We can go as soon as you're ready.
Kobato?
I admire Fujimoto.
Yes.
He's really something.
I'll do my best.
Yes.
Okay everyone, let's call Santa!
Okay! Santa!
Hey it's Santa!
Wow Santa!
Santa really came!
Santa!
Huh? Teacher Fujimoto?
No...
You're Santa, aren't you?
Santa?
Are you Teacher Fujimoto?
This person is Santa!
That's right, isn't it, Santa?
So! Everyone, what do you think Santa
has brought for you today?
Santa! My present!
Please give me my present!
Thank you!
Thank you very much, Santa!
Well then everyone, shall we have some cake?
Yes!
Hmph!
What do you say I go and get my present, too?
Wonderful job, Fujimoto.
I'll tidy up, so you go on ahead.
I mean, it's Christmas and all...
Don't bother going out of your way for me.
Darn. Why should I have to?
Shut up. Christmas is our busiest season.
Always taking advantage of me.
Merry Christmas!
What are you guys up to?
You look pretty good in that.
Hi Kobato!
Kobato?
I see. Fujimoto was holding it
all in because it's Christmas.
I think I made his pain worse.
Now he really hates me.
But why...
Why does it...
Why does that hurt me so much?
He's on your mind that much, is he?
I don't know. It's not intentional.
I just think about him.
I don't know why, but when I think
about him I get a pain in my heart.
I see.
Domoto?
I've finally figured out the best present for you.
Thank you, please come again.
A Christmas present.
Don't get me wrong.
It isn't for you.
I want you to take this up to Kobato.
She's waiting at the lookout.
Go, please. I'll cover for you here.
Wait a minute. Why me?
It's Christmas but she's feeling upset.
So?
It's your attitude that's hurting her!
But Kobato thinks she's to blame.
She wants to apologize to you.
She's waiting up there. Kobato.
She's waiting all alone!
Fujimoto?
It's not your fault.
You did nothing wrong.
You have nothing to feel bad about.
Huh?
So... well, why do you let it
bother you in the first place?
Um... Could you by chance be telling
me that, you are not angry?
I never was mad at you...
...from the very beginning!
B-But now you are! You're angry!
Anyway, just don't worry about it.
Okay.
Oh, right. This is from Domoto.
To Kobato,
Were you able to make up with Fujimoto?
This is my Christmas present to you.
To Kobato,
Were you able to make up with Fujimoto?
This is my Christmas present to you.
Umm...
Were you able to make up with Fujimoto?
That is my Christmas present to you.
I'm sorry if this guy is mean to you.
Huh?
Merry Christmas...
Fujimoto, you are my Christmas
present from Domoto?
Kobato, what did Domoto say
when he told you to wait here?
He said he'd bring a present that
would be perfect for me.
Domoto helped us be friends again.
That guy...
Uh, Hey!
Look Fujimoto, snow!
I know what snow looks like.
It's so pretty!
Flowers blossom in the spring
Skies in the summer reach far and wide
Every time I think of this
Precious thoughts spread across in my heart
In the morning when it rains
On those days when the windows stay closed
My heart shimmers with the light
Light shining brightly above the clouds
The voices are calling to me
From way over yonder, from far I can hear
Voices of laughter
Voices of singing
Echoing voices of the wind
Snow can be pretty too, can't it?
Yes!
In happiness and in sadness
In any case, when winter turns to spring...
In all I behold and all that I live for
It'll be time to say goodbye to Dobato.
With my hand in your hand
Your hand in my hand
Together, we are one and whole
Everyone dreams of flying
But they let gravity trick them
Honestly, everyone is already able to fly
I bet the reason that child looks so terribly sad
Is because he
Accidentally lost his shadow somewhere
In that case
If I could just tell you, "Thank you,"
And you laugh and reply, "Thank you"
That exchange would fill you with joy
It would make you feel so happy
There's nothing to worry about
Since we're together
It's strange how I'm crying
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...The Travelers.
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...The Travelers.